ここは？
This place!
ノノハ…　何を？
Nonoha?
What are...
フ　フリーセル…。
F-Freecell!
（フリーセル）カイト…　パズルをしよう。
えっ！？
Kaito, let's do a puzzle.
どうしたの？
僕を救うんじゃなかったの？
What is it?
Weren't you going to save me?
見えてるよ　カイト。
I can see it, Kaito.
うわっ…。
（フリーセル）僕たちのパズルタイムが…。
Our puzzle time!
何だ…　今のは…。
What was that just now?
まさか…。
Don't tell me...
lost te saguri de sagashiteta
Lost, trying to find it blindly with my hands.
tozasareta mirai no kotae nante doko ni mo nai
But the key to the locked future is nowhere to be found.
hashiru shoudou ima kaidoku funou
Undecipherable urges surging.
found kudaketa hazu no unmei wo
I found the fate I believed broken.
mijukuna yume no naka de kikoetekitan da
I heard it in my immature dream.
saigo made I'll be there for you
I'll be there for you till the very end.
tachitomaranai kono hari dake wa
I can't stop. I hear nothing else.
boku no asu wo kizamu oto tsukisasu
How this needle carves my future.
shinjitsu kara nigetara ima
I'm running away from the truth now.
genjitsu ni mo maketara ima
I'm losing to reality now.
nani ga nokoru no (nokoru no)
What will be left?
kazoekirenai kono kizu dake ga
The countless scars on my body
boku no kinou wo zanzou toshite kataru
are the only thing telling the story of my past.
unmei ga hodokete mo ima
Even if fate falls apart now,
sonzai wo kowashite mo ima
even if existence shatters now,
boku no michi wo yuku yo
I'm walking down my own path.
It's now or never.
This is what they say: "Live your life today."
There will always be, there will always be a way.
Fools' Puzzles Again
（エレナ）クロンダイクという名前について
ＰＯＧで調査を続けてるけど…。
The POG has been investigating this "Klondike" name.
（ギャモン）何か　分かったのか？
やっぱり　名前だけじゃねぇ…。
You learn anything?
Sure enough, just the name.
ケッ　ＰＯＧも使えねえな。
Jeez, the POG ain't no use!
だったら　自分で調べなさいよ！
In that case, do your own investigating!
I will report next.
（キュービック）次　僕から報告するね。
アナのお姉さん　イブ・グラム。
Ana's big sister, Eve Gram...
and Pinochle...
そして　ピノクル。
２人のリングの残骸を調べた結果→
I've examined the remains of their rings, and the result...
やはり　両方とも
レプリカだと判明したよ。
As I predicted, they're both replica rings.
えっ！？
ちょ　ちょっと待って。
H-Hold on a minute.
Wasn't it the Orpheus Order themselves
オルペウス・オーダーのやつら→
自分たちのリングは　本物だって
言ってなかったか？
who said their rings were real?
うん。　自分たちは　本物の
ファイ・ブレインの子供だって…。
Yeah, and that they're the true children of the Phi Brain.
少なくとも　２人のリングは
レプリカに間違いないね。
At any rate, there's no doubt their rings were replicas.
じゃあ　他の人たちも？
And the others' too?
フリーセルのやつ　まがいもののリングを
本物にしたって言ってたよな。
Freecell said he made his fake ring into a real one.
レプリカを　本物に？
そんなことって　あるのかしら？
A replica into a real one?
Is that possible?
（キュービック）理論上は
ありえないはずだけど…。
It shouldn't be, even theoretically.
What's more, he said his mom dying wasn't Kaito's fault, huh?
おまけに　母親が死んだのは
カイトのせいじゃねえって→
言い出したんだよなぁ。
お母さんのことを
大好きって言ったり→
He said that he loved his mother,
大嫌いって
言ったりしてたんだよね。
but also that he hated her, right?
あっ！　カイト？
Kaito?
（ミゼルカ）ダウト　メランコリィを見なかった？
どこにも居ないのよ。
Doubt, have you seen Melancholy?
I can't find her anywhere.
（ダウト）いや。
そう…　困った子…。
No.
Oh, that child...
どういうことかしらね。
I wonder what's going on?
ヘルベルトが敗れて
フリーセルも姿を見せなくなった。
Herbert was beaten, and Freecell has disappeared.
私たちへの新しい使命も
下されない。
We aren't receiving any new orders.
知ったことではない。
I care nothing for that.
私は　クロンダイク様からの
お言葉を待つ。
I wait for word from Lord Klondike.
あっ。
それだけだ。
That is all.
（ホイスト）フリーセルの行方は　依然
つかめておりません。
We remain unable to locate Freecell.
データ収集用のレプリカ・リングで→
Him using the replica ring to awaken to his Phi Brain potential
ファイ・ブレインとして覚醒を始めるとは
計算外でした。
was not in our calculations.
（クロンダイク）計算で導き出せない
答えなどない。
There is no outcome that the calculations do not produce.
それは
君のミスにすぎないのだよ。
This is nothing more than your mistake.
分かるかね。
[TEL]（ホイスト）申し訳ございません。
Do you understand?
I'm very sorry.
この世界に　私の計算どおりに
進まぬものなどない。
Nothing in this world fails to proceed by my calculations.
ミスは　速やかに　訂正せねば
ならんのだよ。　ミスター　ホイスト。
This mistake must be quickly addressed,
Mr. Whist.
承知いたしました　クロンダイク様。
Understood, Lord Klondike.
（メランコリィ）カビ臭いお城より
こういう　かわいいお部屋の方が→
This cute place suits me much more
than some moldy old castle, don't you think?
私には　似合うと思わない？
はい。　よくお似合いです。
Yes, it suits you well.
ねえねえ　これから何が起きるの？
さあ　私にも分かりません。
Hey, so what's gonna happen now?
Even I do not know.
え～っ！？　つまんない。
Huh? That's boring!
先の展開は　読めない方が
面白いものですよ。　メランコリィ様。
Not knowing how something will develop
makes it more interesting, Lady Melancholy.
（ドアを閉める音）
そうかしら？
Really?
どう転んでも…　楽しみようは
あるものです。
No matter how the chips fall, there is always enjoyment.
カイト　どこ行っちゃったんだろう？
Where did Kaito run off to?
先に帰っちゃったのかな？
Did he go home without me?
ママの…　形見か…。
A "memento of Mama," huh?
ギャモン　どうしたの？
それは　こっちのセリフだ。
Gammon, what's going on?
That's my line, Q-taro!
キュー太郎！
てめえ　一体　何を隠してやがる。
What the hell are you hiding?
えっ！？　な　何の話？
W-What are you talking about?
とぼけるんじゃねえ。
うっ！
Quit acting dumb.
きのうの夜
カイトの脳が活性化してたんだ。
Last night, Kaito's brainwaves were active.
また　監視してたのかよ！
で…。
You're still monitoring him?!
And?
その活性化のパターンが…　以前　カイトが
ファイ・ブレインとして目覚めかけ→
The activation pattern
matched the pattern from when he approached
未来を見ていた頃と
そっくりだったんだ。
はぁ…。
Phi Brain potential and saw the future.
初めは　センサーの故障かと
思ったんだけど…。
At first, I thought maybe the sensors were broken, but...
あいつは　オルペウスの腕輪を
捨てたんだ。
He trashed the Orpheus Order's armband.
…んなこと　ありえねえだろう。
僕も　そう思う…。
This ain't possible, right?
I thought so too.
But...
けど…。
心の声
あれは　夢なんかじゃねえ。
That wasn't a dream.
心の声
あの感覚　間違いねえ。
俺が見たのは　未来だ！
That sensation...
I'm sure of it.
What I saw was... the future.
心の声
それに　あのリングの輝き…。
Also, that ring's glow...
心の声
フリーセルは…　フリーセルは　本当に…。
Freecell...
Is Freecell really...
あっ…　あいつは？　えっ。
Him!
てめえ！　何にしてやがった！？
Bastard, what the hell have you done?!
It seems Sir Freecell is not with you.
フリーセル様は　あなたのもとには
いらっしゃらないようですね。
フリーセル？　どういうことだ？
Freecell?
What are you talking about?
ひょっとしてと思い
来てみましたが→
I came here thinking perhaps he had.
I shall explore other avenues.
他を当たってみましょう。　では…。
待て！
Goodbye.
Wait!
何か？
Yes?
フリーセルたちのリングは…
レプリカなんだな？
Freecell's and the others' rings are replicas, aren't they?
よろしかったら　中で…。
Get in, if you want.
カイト様のおっしゃるとおり
フリーセル様たちのリングは　レプリカです。
As you said, Sir Freecell and the others own replica rings.
彼らも　データを取るための
サンプルにすぎないのです。
They are samples for collecting data, nothing more.
あなたとのゲームのおかげで
いいデータが取れました。
Thanks to their games with you,
we acquired some splendid data.
ご協力　感謝いたします。
We're grateful for your cooperation.
Why are you looking for Freecell?
なんで　フリーセルを捜してる？
Sir Freecell has begun to awaken his Phi Brain potential.
フリーセル様は　ファイ・ブレインとして
覚醒を始めました。
レプリカ・リングで　そのようなことが
起こるとは→
For something like that to happen with
我々も　想定していなかった
事態です。
a replica ring was outside our assumptions.
データは　全て回収しなければ…。
We must collect all data.
回想
フリーセル様にお会いしたら　私が
捜していたとお伝えください。
If you encounter Sir Freecell, please tell him I am looking for him.
やっぱり　フリーセルは
心の声
ファイ・ブレインに…。　だとしたら…。
Sure enough, Freecell's becoming a Phi Brain!
In which case...
But you can't beat me as you are now.
（フリーセル）今の君では
回想
僕に勝てない。　だって　僕は…。
After all, I'm...
（ピノクル）待っててね　フリーセル。
僕も　頑張るからね。
Just wait, Freecell.
I'll do my best.
（ルーク）なんだって！？
What did you say?!
ルーク　愚者のパズルに挑ませてくれ。
Rook...
Let me challenge a Fools' Puzzle.
（ギャモン）カイトが居ねえだと！？
Kaito ain't here?!
Yeah, I went to get him this morning and he was gone.
うん…　朝　迎えに行ったら
居なくて→
先に　学校　来てるのかなって
思ったんだけど…。
I figured he'd just come to school early, but...
（アナ）来てなかったんだ。
うん。　どうしちゃったんだろう。
...he wasn't here.
Yeah...
I wonder what happened.
（エレナ）そういえば　きのう
カイトに頼まれて→
Come to think of it, Kaito asked me to
ルーク様に連絡をとったわ。
えっ！？　一体　何の用で？
contact Sir Rook yesterday.
What the heck for?
詳しいことは聞いてないけど…
会いたいと伝えてくれって。
I didn't get any specifics.
He just said, "Tell him I want to meet him."
何か　関係あるのかしら？
はぁ。
Could that have something to do with it?
この奥に…。
（ビショップ）はい。　パズルがございます。
So, inside here...
Yes, there is a puzzle.
かつて　ルーク様が　あなたを
ファイ・ブレインへと導くために造った→
The Fools' Puzzle that Sir Rook created to lead you
愚者のパズルが…。
to your Phi Brain potential.
本当に挑むんだね　カイト。
ああ。
You're really going to challenge it, Kaito?
Yeah!
私は反対です。
もう一度　お考えください。
I, for one, object.
Please reconsider.
俺は　強くならなきゃ
いけねえんだ。
I gotta get stronger,
フリーセルと戦って　救うために…。
to battle Freecell and then save him.
あいつ…　約束も　母親も
どうでもいいって言いやがった。
That guy...
He friggin' said he didn't care about the promise, or his mom.
それだけ　リングに飲まれてしまって
いるということかな。
That's how deeply he's been swallowed up by the ring?
あいつを　あいつを止めなきゃ…。
I...
I gotta stop him.
だけど　今の俺じゃ
勝ち目は　ねえ。
But the way I am now, I have no chance of winning.
Because he's begun to awaken his Phi Brain potential?
（ビショップ）彼が　ファイ・ブレインとして
目覚め始めているからですか？
That's why you will challenge a Fools' Puzzle,
だから　愚者のパズルに挑み
あなたも…。
so that you can too?
ならねえよ。
誰が　ファイ・ブレインなんかに…。
Forget it.
I won't be a Phi Brain.
ならずに　強くなってやる！
I'll get stronger without doing that.
ルーク様　危険です。　止めるべきです。
Sir Rook, this is dangerous.
We must stop him.
カイトの気持ちは　変わらないよ。
僕の気持ちもね…。
Kaito's feelings won't change.
Neither will mine.
パズルタイムの…　始まりだ！
It's...
puzzle time!
あっ…。　これは…。
This is...
迷路か…。
a maze?
砂時計…。　決められた時間で　道を
探し出し　出口まで行けってのか？
An hourglass...
I have to find the route in a set time and make it to the exit?
とにかく　行ってみるしかねえな！
Anyway, I've just gotta try!
こいつは…。　うっ。
This thing...
石像正面の落とし穴。
Pitfalls in front of the stone faces?
こいつをよけながら
進めってことか。
I've gotta go forward while avoiding these things, huh?
えっ。　ダメだ。
これ以上は進めねえ。
It's no good. I can't go any farther.
正面を向いた像の前が
落とし穴だとすると→
If the stone faces have pitfalls in front of them,
八方ふさがり…　ということは…。
I'm boxed in all eight ways.
残るは　後ろを向いたこの像。
That leaves this one, which faces to the rear.
ん？　動くぞ。
（動く音）
It moves!
心の声
石像は　床のパネル１つ分
動かすことができる。
The stone faces can move one floor panel.
心の声
おそらく　動かせるのは
１体につき　１度だけ。
Maybe each can only be moved once.
そうか！　石像を動かして
道を造れるってことか！
I get it! You gotta move the stone faces to make your path!
よし！
Let's do this!
あっ！
どうしたの？　キューちゃん。
What is it, Cubie?
こ　これは！？
Th-This is...
カイトが　パズルを解いている！
Kaito is solving a puzzle.
（アナ・ノノハ）えっ！？
（ギャモン）なんだと！？
What'd you say?!
Don't tell me he's been ambushed by the Orpheus Order!
（エレナ）まさか　オルペウス・オーダーに
襲われてるの！？
キューちゃん！
待って！　今　マップを出す。
Cubie!
Hold on, I'll pull up a map.
Huh? No way!
えっ！？　ウソ…。
何？
What?
どうした？
心当たりでもあるのか？
You got an idea or something? What?
愚者のパズルだと！
ええ。　それも　ルーク様が造った…。
A Fools' Puzzle?!
Yes, what's more, one that Sir Rook made.
じゃあ　ルーク君も　一緒ってこと？
So, Rook is with him?
思考速度が　どんどん
上昇している。
His thought speed is increasing rapidly.
なんで　愚者のパズルに　カイトが？
What's Kaito doing in a Fools' Puzzle?
アナが思うに
あの２人なら　大丈夫。
I think... the two of them will be okay.
Ana...
アナ…。
信じよう！　カイトとルークを。
Let's believe in them, in Kaito and Rook.
うっ！　うわっ！　何！？　うっ！
What?!
Dammit, yet another trap, huh?!
くそっ！
さらなる　トラップってわけか！
僕は　今でも自分が許せない。
ルーク様。
Even now, I can't forgive myself.
Sir Rook...
よくも　こんな…　むごいパズルを
造ったものだとね。
Not for making such a cold-hearted puzzle.
That was...
それは…
腕輪に飲まれていたのです。
You were swallowed up by the Armband.
ルーク様の責任では…。
It's not your fault, Sir Rook.
そう。　腕輪に飲まれ
ファイ・ブレインとして覚醒しようとした。
Yes, swallowed up by the Armband,
I tried to awaken my Phi Brain potential.
だからこそ　同じ過ちを
誰かに繰り返させたくない。
Which is precisely why I don't want
anyone else to make the same mistake.
同じ思いを　誰かに
させたくないんだ。
I don't want anyone to feel that way.
Not Kaito, and not myself.
カイトも…　僕も…。
おはっ。
うわっ…　あはっ。
これで…　最後だ！　えっ。
This is the end!
思考速度が戻っていく。
His thought speed is going back to normal.
Looks like he solved the puzzle, huh?
パズルを解放したみてえだな。
カイトは？
無事だよ。　ケガもしてない。
How's Kaito?
He's fine, no injuries.
はぁ…　よかった！
Thank goodness.
Ｆ。
間違いねえ…　フリーセルだ。
"F"?
No doubt about it.
It's Freecell!
先に解放していたと
いうのですか？
You're saying that he solved it first?
この愚者のパズルを…。
This Fools' Puzzle?
ルーク　他の愚者のパズルに
案内してくれ。
Rook, take me to another Fools' Puzzle,
a more extreme one!
もっと　強烈なやつに！
この愚者のパズルは　カイトが　腕輪を
つけていた頃に造ったものだよ。
I made this Fools' Puzzle
when you were still wearing the Orpheus Armband.
だから　何だってんだ？
腕輪の力に頼らず　あれを解いた。
So the heck what?
You solved it without relying on the Armband's power.
それだけ　カイトが
強くなってるってことさ。
That's how much stronger you've become.
But I still gotta do it.
それでも　やるしかねえんだ。
やつを止めるためには
強くなるしか！
To stop him, I need to get even stronger!
そうだね。　やるしかない。
That's right, you have to do it.
僕は信じてる。
カイトなら　できるって。
I believe.
I believe you can do it.
僕の心を　腕輪の呪縛から
解き放ってくれた　カイトなら…。
You freed my mind from the Armband's spell, Kaito.
ルーク。
Rook...
今度は　僕も一緒だよ　カイト。
This time, I'll be with you, Kaito.
ふっ…　フリーセル様。
Sir Freecell...
カイトを見張っていれば
僕に会えると思ったんでしょう？
You thought by watching Kaito
you'd find me, didn't you?
正解。
Bingo!
（フリーセル）
僕の精神は　リングとシンクロした。
My psyche synchronized with the ring.
そして　目覚めたんだ。
And so, I awakened.
目覚めた瞬間…
いろいろなものが見えたよ。
The moment I awakened...
I could see so many things.
（ホイスト）いろいろ…　ですか？
Many things?
Yes.
（フリーセル）そう。　だから　今日
あそこで　君を待ってたんだ。
That's why I waited for you there today.
何でも見えているんだよ。
君のこと。　君の知っていること。
I can see everything.
About you,
and what you know.
君と僕が…　望む未来。
And the future that...
you and I want.
eiyuu kidori itsu datte shinjita muteki no kankaku
I think I'm a hero and believe that I'm invincible.
tatakatte iru no wa chikyuu no tame nanka janai
I'm not fighting for the world.
motto mai peesu de
It's for a more personal,
sou motto shoujikina negai no tame
a more honest wish.
nando to naku kizutsuite mo
No matter how many times I'm hurt